ableton.com 2018-03-28

# Ableton Privacy Policy | Ableton

Ableton handles all customers’ personal data with the utmost discretion. Data will only be collected within the scope of what is technically necessary. On no account, data shall be transferred to third parties for invalid reasons.

## 1\. Definitions

This privacy policy is based on the definitions used in the German Data Protection Act (BDSG), in particular:

  *  **personal data** – any information concerning the personal or material circumstances of an identified or identifiable individual, for instance, name, address, date of birth, e-mail address and IP address,
  *  **data processing** – the storage, modification, transfer, blocking and erasure of personal data, 
  *  **storage** – the entry, recording or preservation of personal data on a storage medium so that they can be processed or used again,
  *  **modification** – the alteration of the substance of stored personal data,
  *  **transfer** – the disclosure to a third party of personal data stored or obtained by means of data processing either through transmission of the data to the third party or through the third party inspecting or retrieving data held ready for inspection or retrieval,
  *  **blocking** – labelling stored personal data so as to restrict their further processing or use,
  *  **erasure** – the deletion of stored personal data,
  *  **data use** – any utilization of personal data other than data processing,
  *  **rendering anonymous** – the modification of personal data so that the information concerning personal or material circumstances can no longer or only with a disproportionate amount of time, expense and labor be attributed to an identified or identifiable individual,
  *  **aliasing** – replacing a person’s name and other identifying characteristics with a label, in order to preclude identification of the data subject or to render such identification substantially difficult.

## 2\. Scope and intended purpose of the data collected

Personal data shall be collected or used, insofar as this is necessary for the use of the website and for the purchase of products. In particular, data shall be collected and used in order to process user interactions and to enable contact with the web shop.

Generally, you can use our website without entering personal data. However, for some functions certain information is necessary.

 **2.1 Inventory data (collection/use and erasure)**

Personal data shall only be collected and used insofar as this is necessary for the establishment, structuring or modification of contractual relationships with customers or the initiation and conclusion of contractual agreements in the context of the use of the website (inventory data).

Inventory data shall be erased promptly once it is no longer needed for the purposes specified in this section. However, this shall not apply insofar as it is collected and used as usage data and/or billing data within the meaning of sections 2.2 and/or 2.3 below, respectively, or on the basis of statutory regulations.

 **2.2 Usage data (collection/use and erasure)**

Only to the extent necessary, personal data shall be collected and used with respect to the use of our website for initiating, concluding and executing contractual agreements. This shall include, among other things, data regarding user characteristics (name, IP address, postal address, email address), data regarding the beginning, end and extent of use of the web pages, as well as data regarding the telemedia services and other services used. We may also transfer such data to our subcontractors insofar and for as long as this is necessary for the shipping of goods.

As a general rule, collected usage data shall be erased or rendered anonymous once the corresponding user interaction has been completed, unless such data has been collected/used as inventory or billing data pursuant to sections 2.1 above and/or 2.3 below, respectively, or pursuant to statutory regulation. Data may be used beyond the completion of user interaction only insofar as it is needed for further interactions, for billing or for other services.

 **2.3 Billing data (determination of charges and billing)**

Data may be collected and used insofar as it is necessary for determining charges (e.g., purchasing prices) and processing payments. This shall include the collection and processing of usage data specified under section 2.2 above as well as data needed to determine the charges owed, such as payment records and accounting data.

Billing data may be collected and used beyond completion of the billing cycle (e.g., full payment of invoices) only insofar as it is required by law or insofar as such data qualifies as inventory or usage data pursuant to sections 2.1 and/or 2.2 above, respectively, or pursuant to statutory regulation.

Insofar as there are clear indications that our website has been used with the intent of not paying (in full) for such use, we are entitled to make use of the particular users’ personal data beyond the end of the data use procedure to the extent necessary for prosecution. Once this is no longer the case, and assuming there is no further obligation to use such data, we will delete the data promptly.

## 3\. Automatically collected data

 **3.1 Server log file**

Our web servers automatically save the following data with every visit: the visitor’s IP address, date and time, accessed page/name of the accessed file, notification regarding the success of access/retrieval, the transferred data amount, the website from which the request was sent (“referrer”) and information about the web browser and operating system that were used for such access.

The IP address shall be automatically rendered anonymous 24 hours after the visit, at the latest. It shall be used exclusively for the purposes of anti-abuse measures and the detection of errors.

 **3.2 Aliased analysis of user behavior and commercial networks**

We use different technical means to examine the user behavior and the interests of the visitors of our website by aliasing or by rendering the data anonymous. Moreover, we use commercial networks to control commercial ads. To this end, we also use so-called “cookies”. Cookies are small text files, which are saved to your device. Generally, you can choose in your browser preferences if and which cookies may be saved to your device.

Through the web services [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (EU) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (US) you can determine which cookies you allow for online ads and which you want to block.

Irrespectively of these general means to control the use of cookies, almost all of the cookies we use offer an individual possibility to opt-out:

 **3.2.1 Google Universal Analytics** – This website uses Google Universal Analytics, a web-analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Universal Analytics uses so-called “cookies“, text files, which are saved to your computer and which allow for an analysis of your use of the website. The cookie-generated data regarding your use of this website will generally be forwarded to a Google server in the USA and stored there. For this website, the IP anonymization is activated, meaning your IP address will be truncated by Google within Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area beforehand. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to a Google server in the USA and is shortened there. 

Google will use this data as a processor in accordance with § 11 of the German Data Protection Act (BDSG), in order to analyze your use of the website, to draft reports about website activities and to perform further services for the website’s operator in connection to website usage and internet usage. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Universal Analytics is not merged with other data held by Google.

Additionally, a so-called User-ID will be used. This ID is not assigned to a particular device but to you personally. The User-ID enables the analysis of your behavior across devices (smartphone, tablet, notebook). The allocation of the User-ID to a user ensues once we have unequivocally identified you as a user. This happens generally when you are using your Ableton user account. As soon as you have logged-in for the first time, a User-ID is allocated to you accordingly. It contains a unique, persistent, and non-personally identifiable string for a signed user. Once you log into our website the User-ID is sent to Google Universal Analytics. As far as Google is concerned, [the User-ID functions as your alias](https://support.google.com/analytics/?hl=en#topic=3544906). Google connects your online behavior and the User-ID to a profile. Google only receives the User-ID, not the information contained in the above-mentioned profile or other personal data of yours. A summarized version of the profile created in this way is accessible to us. We do not attach any other of your personal data to the profile connected to a User-ID.

You can object to the above-described data collection for each respective device by making use of the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en) with future effect. More information on terms and services and safeguarding your data can be found here:

Moreover, you can object to the transfer of a User-ID to Google by writing an e-mail to privacy[at]Ableton[dot]com.

You can prevent Google’s collection of the cookie-generated data related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as its processing by Google by downloading and installing the [browser plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) offered by Google. 

Moreover, the operator of this website uses Google Universal Analytics to evaluate data from AdWords and the Double-Click-Cookie for statistical purposes. You can stop this at any time by using the [Google Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/), by changing the setting to “OFF”.

 **3.2.2 Google Dynamic Remarketing** – We use Google’s Dynamic Remarketing. To run interest-based ads within the Google commercial network, Google saves a cookie to your device, which stores data regarding your browsing habits with an alias. The Google Ads Preference Manager lets you see at any time, which conclusions Google draws from the cookie. Moreover, you also have the option there to make changes or to deactivate the data collection.

 **3.2.3 Facebook Retargeting** – On our website we use Facebook Exchange. To run interest-based ads within the Facebook commercial network, Facebook saves a cookie to your device, which stores data regarding your browsing habits with an alias. You can prohibit Facebook from collecting this data by selecting the applicable function pursuant to the web services [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (EU) and [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (US). Provided that you have a Facebook account, [Facebook’s Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy) applies.

 **3.2.4 Optimizely** – In order to optimize our website, we use the tool “Optimizely”. Your user behavior is analyzed in a cookie on our website. You can [object](https://www.optimizely.com/opt_out/) to the use of Optimizely at any time.

 **3.2.5 Crazy Egg** – In order to optimize our website, we use the tool “Crazy Egg”. A cookie analyzes your user behavior (particularly your clicks) on our website. You can [object](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out) to the use of Crazy Egg at any time.

 **3.2.6 Mouseflow** – With Mouseflow’s help we examine the user behavior of our website’s visitors. Mouseflow stores the movement and click behavior of the mouse cursor on the website in a cookie. We use this information to optimize our website. You can [object](https://mouseflow.com/opt-out/) to the use of Mouseflow at any time.

 **3.3 Collecting usage data in anonymous form as part of the Ableton Live and Ableton Suite (both hereinafter referred to as “Software“) Usage Reports**

If the “Usage Report“ function has been activated in the Software settings, data about the use of the Software by the user are transferred to us in anonymous form when there is an internet connection. Such data includes inter alia:

  * user behavior regarding the Software and documents used (files) during the program runtime, and
  * the set-up of the computer on which the Software is installed, in particular the operating system (OS), the Software version installed including third party add-ons and extensions thereto if applicable (Max for Live, Plug Ins, Rewire Slave and Hosts, drivers, and add-ons), the hardware configuration (computer system, audio interfaces and MIDI interfaces, graphics card) and the content from the Ableton Library, Partner Instruments, M4L-devices and Sound Library.

This data is used to develop the Software further, and to adapt it to user requirements, and to optimize it. Personal user profiles shall not be created.

 **3.4 Saving aliased usage data as part of the online Software activation**

In the event that you activate the Software online, aliased authentication information will be stored on your hardware device for the purpose of connecting the Software to your User Account, enabling the Software to obtain the information pertaining to your license(s) that is/are stored in your User Account.

## 4\. User entries on the website

 **4.1 Newsletter**

If you sign up for our newsletter we save your e-mail address, in order to send you the newsletter. You receive the newsletter only if you have subscribed to it. Unsubscribing from the newsletter is possible at any time and free of charge. To do so, please click on the link at the end of every newsletter or change the preferences of your user account accordingly.

Our e-mail communication can contain so-called hyperlinks („links“), which contain random but unambiguous identification numbers. We (or external service providers working for us, e.g., web-analysis service providers) can collect and store these identification numbers when your computer accesses these links, in order to retrieve additional information from our servers. The identification numbers in those links are neither merged with your name, nor your postal address or other personal data, unless you have explicitly allowed us to send information specifically matching your interests to you. We use these links and information regarding your accesses, in order to track your usage of our e-mails and our website and to record and evaluate the success of particular marketing measures. We use this information to improve our website and our e-mail newsletter, particularly by aligning our information and offers with the users’ individual interests and needs.

You can [object](http://www.scarabresearch.com/privacy/#optout) to the above-described processing and use of link-data. When you choose this option, an anonymous “opt-out” cookie is saved to your web browser, which informs our web server about your objection and thereby prevents the data collection. The opt-out cookie remains active within the browser you use until you delete it with the means provided by this browser. When you delete the cookie or use a different browser or computer, we will no longer be able to discern your previous objection.

 **4.2 Shop**

When you purchase products in our shop, we require the information necessary for the performance of the purchasing agreement, including the information necessary to process the payment. Setting up a user account is necessary in order to be able to use our products. This also applies to the free Trial Version.

 **4.3 Handling of data in case of suspected unlawful use**

Insofar as there are factual indications of fraudulent acquisition or other illegal uses of our services, we will be entitled to collect and exploit personal data in order to detect and prevent such unlawful use, as well as to enforce our own legal claims.

## 5. External service providers

For certain activities in connection with our website and our e-mail communication we commissioned external service providers (e.g., data processing centers). These service providers process data exclusively in accordance with our instructions, they are also bound by these privacy policy terms and are subject to our control. These service providers must not, under any circumstances, use data which they collected or processed on our behalf for their own purposes.

## 6. Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA")

Ableton does not knowingly collect or use personal information from children under 13 years without containing verifiable consent from their parents. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s internet usage and to help enforce this privacy policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information without their permission.

## 7\. Criminal prosecution

In a given case, the obligation to provide information about inventory data for purposes of criminal prosecution, warding off danger and/or for use by the police authorities of the German Länder and other authorities can arise.

## 8\. Right to access

You have the right to be informed at any time and without cost about the personal data recorded about you, as well as a right to the correction, blocking, and/or erasure of the data, as applicable.

## 9\. Contact for data protection and privacy

If you have any questions regarding the collection, processing, or use of your personal data, in case of requests for information, correction, blocking, and/or erasure of the data, as well for the revocation of any consent given please contact:

Ableton AG, Schoenhauser Allee 6-7, D-10119 Berlin, Germany  
e-mail: privacy[at]ableton[dot]com, Tel: +49 30 288763-0
